The guy I'm about to interview
has a $500 million net worth.
And he invited us out to
his $20 million mansion out here.
This is insane, you guys.
Ben.
It's good to see you.
How you doing?
Thanks for having us out.
This place is incredible.
Is it?
Yes.
And it all could be yours, baby.
Yeah?
Just pull out that checkbook.
Who am I here with today?
You are here with Ben Mala.
What is your net worth?
On paper, it's close to about $500 million.
So you're buying hotels?
We've bought and sold, I couldn't count how many hotels.
At first, I didn't have any money.
And the first thing everybody has to
learn is you have to borrow money.
If you ain't got no money,
you got one choice in life.
You borrow it.
Are you a good salesman?
Me? No, I can't sell.
I can sell ice to Eskimos.
Now, we're in the backyard of
your $30 million mansion right here.
I want everybody to see.
Guys, guys, this is the
most insane backyard I've ever seen.
What's your last message to somebody?
You didn't see the bowling alley.
You got a bowling alley in there too?
What's your last message to somebody trying to
own a place like this in today's world?
They want to become...
Guys, I'm about to interview one of
the richest men in all of Florida.
And in fact, he has a net worth
of over $500 million, half a billion dollars.
It's Ben Mala, one of the most
renowned real estate entrepreneurs in the entire world.
He owns hotels, apartment complexes,
buildings all over the world.
So I'm going to go up to his house.
We're going to meet him
and we're going to interview him.
Figure out how you can start creating wealth
and becoming wealthy through real estate in today's world.
Even if you don't have a lot of money.
So let's go meet up with Ben
and go see what he has to say.
Come on.
Look at this place, you guys.
$20 million mansion.
We got our guy Ben out here front.
He's got the Rolls Royce, the Ferrari.
This place is insane.
Ben.
What's going on, my friend?
How are you?
It's good to see you.
How you doing?
Thanks for having us out.
Thanks for coming.
It's good to see you, sir.
What's going on, sir?
How you doing?
How's everything going?
Doing well.
This place is incredible.
Is it?
Yes.
And it all could be yours, baby.
Yeah.
Just pull out that checkbook.
So that's what we're going
to be talking about today, right?
We know that you became successful, accumulated hundreds
of millions of dollars of wealth through real estate.
This is going to be a master class.
A master class?
I want this to be the best real
estate interview that I've ever done in my life.
Just remember, I'm the master and you're the student.
That's correct.
And that's why I'm here to learn from you.
Very good.
So can we get into things?
Let's do it.
Let's rock and roll.
Amazing.
Who am I here with today?
You're here with Ben Mala.
What is your net worth?
On paper, it's close to about $500 million.
Did you come from a lot of money?
No.
My family was dirt poor.
My father was the ultimate
cheapskate, too, besides being poor.
And for those that don't know, what industry
did you decide to pursue a career in?
Real estate.
How long have you been in the business?
I started in my early 20s
and I'm in my late 50s.
You do the math.
So what was the turning point getting into real estate?
Real estate is probably the most common
way any human being can make money.
Why?
Because you need it.
Everybody needs a place to live.
Everybody needs a place to work.
Everybody needs a place to shop, right?
I mean, it's essential.
At first, we were just into affordable housing
and then we moved into retail and we went
into hotels.
So we're all over the board now.
So you're buying hotels?
We've bought and sold.
I couldn't count how many hotels.
All over Orlando, Tampa, on this
side of the bay, all over.
How do you get the money to buy hotels?
It's just like buying anything else.
The hotel's making money.
You go to the bank and say, okay,
I want to buy this hotel for this price.
They look at it.
They appraise it.
Yeah, it's a good deal at that price.
They're going to give me 80 cents on the dollar.
Maybe the hotel is 75, but with me,
they'll probably push 80 because they really want
the loan.
There's a big misconception in today's world that you
have to have a ton of money to start
creating wealth in real estate.
Do you agree with that?
Or do you think you don't have to have
any money to get in the game at all?
Listen, everybody's on a different level.
You got to get in.
Where you fit in.
Okay.
At first, I didn't have any money.
And the first thing everybody has to
learn is you have to borrow money.
If you ain't got no money,
you got one choice in life.
You borrow it.
There's no other choice.
Where's the best place to borrow money from?
The bank.
But is a bank going to give
you money if you don't have capital?
How do you get money from a bank?
Okay, listen.
If you're just starting out, there's all kinds of ways.
My first deal was a VA loan.
VA loan, you go up to four units, one
to four units, and you get no money down, baby.
All right.
But let's say you weren't in the military.
Then you got to go FHA.
FHA.
FHA is three and a half percent down.
One to four units.
You know what that means?
That means you can buy four units.
The three units will pay all your bills.
And this one here, you
live for free at a minimum.
Or if you really get
lucky, you'll get cash flow too.
Depends on the buy.
It's all in the buy.
You got to buy it right.
That's what real estate's all about.
Setting yourself up to do the deal with the
money from the bank and finding the right deal.
Everything else is common sense and you can pay people.
You know, you got all
kinds of tools in real estate.
I use lawyers.
I use brokers.
I use bankers.
You're just basically putting all the
right pieces in the right place.
Let me ask you this because I want to
talk about debt real quick because a lot of people
are terrified to take on that debt.
Ooh.
I don't want to borrow any money.
But will you live and fucking grow?
Pardon my language.
No, no, no.
Hey, hey.
The point is if you don't borrow money, I
go out and do a deal tomorrow for, say, $10
million, right?
Simple deal.
$10 million.
I put two down and the bank puts eight.
Who's taking all the risk?
The bank.
And yeah, are rates high now?
Yes, they're higher.
But you really got to worry about the rate
being whether it's four or five or six or
seven.
Then that probably ain't the right deal.
You got to have a much bigger cushion
than that and profit to worry about paying the
bank, you know, 6%.
If I borrow a million bucks in
a bank, that's $60,000 a year in interest.
That's $5,000 a month.
That's when you got to figure it out.
The deal's got to make sense.
It's all in buying the right deal
and having a plan for that deal.
Are banks still lending money in today's world
at the same rate that they once were?
Banks have to loan money.
That's how they make money.
If they don't loan money, they don't make no money.
A bank has only worked what the loans are.
Now, if the loans go bad,
that means the banks work less money.
That's when we have opportunities.
So how did you leverage?
That's what we're waiting for to happen right now.
How did you leverage debt to build wealth?
Listen, the first thing you
got to do is get pre-qualified.
If you don't have nothing, but you got to
have a job, come on, you got to have some
kind of income.
The easiest first way to get
in the door is doing FHA.
And if you're a younger
person, you don't buy a house.
You buy a duplex, a triplex, a fourplex,
something that generates income and provides you with
a place to live.
So this way, you don't have the whole
burden of all the bills being on your shoulders.
And later on in life, you get the house.
You know, it's all, everything's steps in life.
Guys, this interview with Ben.
Has been incredible so far, but one thing
that I've noticed from spending a lot of time
with guys like Ben, who's worth half
a billion dollars and other successful people, even
off camera, it's that not only do they
have an incredible team, but at every point in
their career or their business, they had somebody that
was able to help them step by step, get
to that next level and ultimately help guys
like him build a half a billion dollar net
worth.
And I'm talking to you right now.
If you're at a point in your career
where you don't have those people around you, you
don't have those people that are five, 10,
15, 20 steps ahead, even one step ahead, they
get to that next level.
And I want to give you the opportunity right
now to become a member of the number one community
for business owners in the entire
world called the school of mentors.
And I launched and built this community
a couple months ago, and I've already grown
it to over 4,000 members.
And the reason why is because every single
week I bring in the eight figure, the nine
figure, the billion dollar entrepreneurs that I
interview on this channel, guys, just like
Ben, where these huge business owners
will mentor all of our members directly.
You can literally ask your questions
to the people that I'm interviewing.
So that way you can start to build the
business of your dreams and start to build that financial
freedom.
Guys, I've literally had people like Ben,
for example, Todd Napola, who owns over $500
million worth of real estate, come into my
community and teach the members step by step,
how to invest in real estate.
Even if you have no money to your name
at all, literally the blueprint on how to get
access to capital, how to negotiate with banks,
how to find deals, how to make your money
work for you.
When you start to have it coming in guys,
there's not a single platform or community that we
have anywhere else.
In the world.
In the world right now.
And I want to bring you guys my
multi multi multi billion dollar network of people that
I know to mentor you directly
every week on live zoom calls.
So come get mentored from a billionaire.
Come get mentored from an eight figure,
nine figure entrepreneur and watch your life change.
Just like the people that I
interview to join today for free.
All you have to do is go down
to the link in the description of this video.
I can't wait to see you on the inside.
That being said, let's get back
to the interview throughout your career.
What was the most amount of money
that you made in a single year?
You know, we don't really go by the year.
All I can change.
I'll tell you is I sold
a package for 90 something million.
Not that long ago last year.
And it was a package of properties.
I sell deals all the time.
I sold a $34 million hotel.
I only paid 17 for it.
And the money it cost to fix it up.
We did spend 6 million on fixing it up.
But you know where the money came from?
The operating in a hotel.
Not my pocket.
The hotel is making money today.
I bought it.
Fine.
Take all the money the hotel is
making and pump it into fixing it up.
All right.
Then we flipped it for 34.
We've done a lot of deals like that.
We do them all over the board.
We don't care.
What is the best piece of real
estate somebody can buy in today's world?
The best?
Yeah.
Depends how much money you got.
If you're really on the very top
and you're really in the big world.
Big boys.
Like all the guys you run into all the time.
Data centers.
Why?
Because it's the future.
It's a concrete building with a bunch
of shelves in it filled with computers.
And companies will rent that space from you.
They'll stock their computers in it.
You got enough power to keep it cold.
Data centers is the new future in real estate.
Because computers are only going to grow.
Always.
We can't live without computers anymore.
Clouds and everything we do
is run into a data center.
So, you know, I think data centers are the top.
They're the top of the game in real estate.
I've never heard that before.
That's what's going on in real estate.
That's why I'm in real estate
and I don't know what you do.
Yeah.
But anyway, everything's good.
Everything's good in real estate.
Right.
It doesn't matter what real estate you buy
as long as you're buying a good deal.
But let's say somebody has $100,000.
That money is put to the side.
Where would you park that?
The safest place is always
going to be residential income property.
Like multifamily?
Yeah.
Like a fourplex or an eightplex or a
twelveplex or whatever you feel you can handle.
Or however far your money is going to take it.
If you got a hundred grand,
you need to go get pre-qualified.
Because a hundred grand.
Will get you $500,000 property with a $400,000 loan.
So that's what you can do with a hundred grand.
You go out and leverage it up to $500,000.
Now you're going to go out and find
a building that you can buy for $500,000.
That can be turned into a
building worth seven or eight hundred thousand.
You sell that building eventually?
Or refinance it and keep it.
Refinancing is a non-taxable event.
All the money I get was from refinancing.
When I sell a building, I don't touch the money.
So you refinance.
I have to roll into the next deal, baby.
Yeah.
So you refinance, you get the
money back that you put in,
and then you're making money continuously.
You just keep rolling.
It's the way to go.
That's how they set up the system.
Our system is set up in
the right way for people to grow.
You just have to apply yourself and you
have to find the right people to deal with.
And you got to get in with
the right people that are doing it.
Now you've got an incredible house out here.
This is a $20, $30 million mansion out here.
Stop saying $20 million.
$20 million was five years ago.
$30 million mansion.
Could we go up and check it out?
Sure.
I'll give you the nickel tour.
We'll be right back.
Growing up, did you think all this was possible,
to be able to own a place like this?
I mean, not when I was growing up.
It came to me that this was all possible when
I went to work for the guy that had all this.
And that showed me, yes, it
was achievable because he was smart.
It's smarter than me in some ways, but
I was smarter than him in other ways.
That's why we made such a good partnership.
So I knew it was
achievable when I hit about 25.
So you agree that you can only
grow to what you've been exposed to?
That's a good one.
You should write that down.
You might even be able to copyright and sell that.
I got to.
You can only grow to what you expose to.
So I guess, what was that
mindset shift that made you a multimillionaire?
Stop partying.
Stop worrying about what everybody else is doing.
Stop trying to have shit you can't afford.
Get busy and get to work
and have a plan that makes sense.
So was it all worth it?
All the sacrifice?
Of course, because now my kids don't have
to go through all the shit I went through.
Yes, they earned their pay and they paid their dues.
But now they're not.
Now they don't have to go through all
the struggles that I had to go through.
Do you own this house?
Yes, I own the house.
How do you feel about people that say
that you should not own where you live
and only own where other people live?
How do you feel about that?
A lot of people say that
a home is not a good investment.
It's only what you pay for the home.
If you're buying a home
at a price below the market,
how could it not be a good investment?
And most people, the only investment they have,
the average working person their whole life is their home.
It's a forced way of saving money and building equity.
So everybody should have a home.
And then when they get older,
the home should be paid off.
And then they own it free and clear.
And they're sitting on a pile of cash.
Now, we're in the backyard of
your $30 million mansion right here.
I want everybody to see.
Guys, guys, this is the
most insane backyard I've ever seen.
He has a lazy river in his backyard.
What's your last message to somebody?
You didn't see the bowling alley.
You got a bowling alley in there too?
What's your last message to somebody trying to
own a place like this in today's world?
They want to become a multi...
This don't happen overnight.
And did I really need this big place?
No.
Okay?
But I was at the
right time at the right place.
And me and the seller agreed on the right price.
Okay?
So that's what it was all about.
But beyond that though,
like just one more message that
you can kind of give to somebody
where they want to build a
substantial net worth in today's world.
You got to build it.
You got to build it
block by block and never stop.
And as soon as you keep building blocks,
eventually you're going to have all this.
But let's say somebody,
they're constant failure after failure after failure.
Because the plan wasn't right.
You got to have a plan in real estate.
You're not going to fail if you do your homework
and you assert yourself in finding a deal.
You're not going to lose.
But you got to have a
plan to follow that makes sense.
Right?
You got amazing advice, my friend.
Thank you so much for having us out here.
Where can everybody find you at?
Who tuned in?
BenMala.com
Put it on the screen.
Everybody go tap in with Ben Mala on all platforms.
We'll put the links in the description.
This was incredible, my friend.
Thank you so much for your time.
I appreciate you.
You're buying lunch, right?
Yes, sir.
I'm buying lunch.
Steaks, right?
You said steaks?
I got you.